Guide to the Turkish Photography Collection 1910-1990 AD.MC.007
AbuDhabi
Turkey Collection
Bulk, 1930-1960
1910-1990
AD.MC.007
AbuDhabi
15.0 Paige boxes 15000 photos
Box 1-10
Biographical/Historical note
The primary aim of Akkasah, the Center for Photography at New York University Abu Dhabi is to explore the histories and contemporary practices of photography in the Middle East and North Africa, and to establish a major hub for scholarly research on photography in the region. The Middle East and North Africa have rich traditions of documentary, vernacular, and art photography and these traditions have yet to receive the full critical attention they deserve. Akkasah investigates these histories and practices in dialogue with other photographic cultures and traditions from around the world.
Arrangement note
This collection was processed as it was acquired.
Conditions Governing Access note
Digitization of this collection is underway; thumbnail images will be published here as they become available.
Custodial History note
The collection was acquired through various dealers and private collectors in Turkey.
Scope and Contents note
Akkasah’s collection from Turkey currently includes more than 15,000 images from the late Ottoman era and the modern Turkish Republic. The collection is comprised primarily of amateur photographs from family albums and of individual and group portraits taken in various studios across Turkey. Though many date back to the first decade of the 20th century and some are from as late as the 1970s and 1980s, the core of the collection focuses on the period from the 1920s through to the end of the 1950s. The collection also contains a substantial number of orientalist postcards from major Ottoman cities including Istanbul, Cairo, Alexandria, Port Said, Damascus and Beirut.
- Two women, one in traditional clothes. 20.5 x 14.9 cm, Undated; Studio Foto Saray, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Fashion Accessories; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Traditional Dress; Women
- Two covered women in black with a little girl standing on a chair. 16.4 x 13.9 cm, 17 August 1926; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Children; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Head Covers; Ottoman; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Women
- A large multi-generational family group, an older couple is seated in the middle. Studio stamp on the back. 19.4 x 24.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Children; Coats; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Head Covers; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Darulfunun Geography Class (Istanbul University today). 29.7 x 23.7 cm, 1919; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Education; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Fezes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Maps; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; University
- Man in a suit and fez, with a handlebar mustache. 28.5 x 20.3 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Fezes; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mustaches; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- A young woman with a long necklace wearing a long skirt, holding a clutch, in a garden. 28.5 x 18.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Fashion Accessories; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Trees; Turkey; Women
- Small family group, male is wearing a kalpak. 23.2 x 16.4 cm, 19 [-?-] 1929; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Children; Coats; Family; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- An Armenian family, an older couple are seated in the middle. 21.7 x 28.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Armenian Writing; Family Portraits; Fezes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- Military officer in uniform. 29.7 x 19.0 cm, 26 October 1942; Studio Foto H. Anil, Gelibolu, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Gelibolu, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Military; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing; Uniforms
- Primary school class photo outside a building. 21.0 x 26.3 cm, 1966 - 1967; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Children; Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- Military officer, sitting with a cane. 28.0 x 21.9 cm, Undated; Studio Foto Fazil, Manisa, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Manisa, Turkey; Military; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Uniforms
- A collage of different photographs, "Keguyiagopyan" written on the back. 29.5 x 18.5 cm, 1938; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Family; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Soldiers; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Uniforms
- A soldier with glasses, looking off camera. 27.7 x 20.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Military; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Uniforms
- A woman and a small child sitting on a bench. 20.4 x 16.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Children; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Women
- A group at a dinner table. Names of the guests on the front. 19.5 x 23.8 cm, 26 November 1952; Studio Foto Beyaz Saray, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Alcohol; Drinking; Eating; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Restaurants; Studio Photography
- A man with short mustache. 19.9 x 28.2 cm, Undated; Studio Phebus, Constantinople (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Constantinople; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- A family group, man with a white scarf around his neck, girls in patterned dresses. 19.2 x 25.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Children; Family; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- A small family group, a young girl with a sailor's hat sits in the middle. 21.5 x 15.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Family; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Head Covers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Women
- A group of men sitting at table, eating. 18.2 x 24.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Drinking; Eating; Gatherings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Restaurants; Suits; Turkey
- A man with a mustache, wearing a double breasted suit. 20.5 x 14.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- Seven men, five with round eye glasses and one wearing a bow tie. 22.5 x 24.1 cm, Undated; Studio Husnu Kazim, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Bow Ties; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Usak, Turkey
- A small family group, female with a head cover, holds a small child in her lap. 19.9 x 14.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Children; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Head Covers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- A Zeybek, in traditional clothing, wearing a Fez. 24.1 x 15.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Fezes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Mustaches; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Zeybek
- A group of highschool boys and their female teacher. 18.0 x 24.3 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Boys; Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools; Turkey; Women
- A small family group, two small children seated in the middle. 21.0 x 15.7 cm, Undated; Studio Foto Sener, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Children; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey; Women
- An older woman wearing a head cover. 23.2 x 17.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Head Covers; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Women
- A girls school, with students and teachers. 21.7 x 26.5 cm, Undated; Studio Foto Palas, Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- A woman and a young girl seated on a ferry. 21.2 x 15.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Children; Family; Ferry; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- A man with round glasses and pocket square. 29.7 x 18.8 cm, Undated; Studio Foto Rekor Universite, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- Two photos of seated children, "Karolesh and Salaha". 26.7 x 19.5 cm, 14 May 1937; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Ankara, Turkey; Children; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing
- Older veiled woman. 24.7 x 19.3 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 7)
- A woman on a ferry on the Bosphorus, with Kizkulesi (Maiden's Tower) in the background. 24.0 x 17.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Bosphorous; Ferry; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Maiden's Tower; Photographic Prints; Women
- A young couple, woman has updo. 25.7 x 20.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Couple; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- A wedding ceremony, Bayazit Marmara Sinemasi. 21.3 x 26.2 cm, 8 October 1944; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing; Wedding Ceremony
- School girls in uniforms on the stairs of the building. 17.6 x 25.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Uniforms
- A young short-haired girl on a chair. 30.0 x 23.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Children; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handtinting; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- A small family group, man, woman and small child seated on a wicker chair with checkered floors. 29.2 x 18.4 cm, 29 January 1939; Studio Foto Refik, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Balikesir, Turkey; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing
- A family group, one seated female, one seated male, two standing males in suits. 31.2 x 24.9 cm, Undated; Servanis, Theodore (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Constantinople; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- Two standing women and one girl standing on a chair with checkered dress. 23.8 x 17.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Children; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Women
- A couple, female wears a striped dress and male in suit. 17.4 x 24.7 cm, 9 May 1938; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Couple; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Suits; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- Two women looking off camera. 21.3 x 24.0 cm, Undated; Studio Foto Rekor, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- School boys of varied ages in suits. J. Claude Popin (signature). 26.2 x 32.5 cm, Undated; Popin, J. Claude (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Boys; Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools; Suits; Turkey
- Two seated covered females, one seated male in light suit, one standing male with bow tie and one standing youth. 26.1 x 21.3 cm, 1907; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Family Portraits; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Head Covers; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Three men on a boat, pulling another boat. 17.5 x 22.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Boats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Seas; Turkey
- Children in front, women in second row, and men standing third row. 23.2 x 27.8 cm, 18 April 1932; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Children; Countryside; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Handtinting; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- A man with round glasses, pocket square and badge on his jacket. 29.3 x 19.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- A class of school girls of varied ages in dresses and holding diplomas. 20.0 x 25.7 cm, Undated; Studio Guyse, Tunis, Tunisia (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Architecture; Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools; Turkey; Women
- Two females embracing, younger girl in white dress, older woman in black dress. 23.7 x 15.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Family; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Women
- Smiling, older woman. 23.7 x 17.9 cm, Undated; Studio Atlantis, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Women
- Three females sitting on stairs in front of the Municipality. 26.7 x 21.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Children; Family; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Women
- Man, seated profile, with round glasses, mustache and pocket square. 29.6 x 19.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 11)
- A young couple, man is in military uniform. 22.7 x 17.1 cm, 3 February 1949; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Couple; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Uniforms
- A young couple, man in military uniform and woman in a light dress with ruffles and a headband. 32.0 x 22.0 cm, Undated; Studio Foto Sumer, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Couple; Gelatin Silver Prints; Makeup; Military; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Uniforms
- Young men with long hair seated around a table, looking at one man writing. Man in the middle has glasses. 14.6 x 24.0 cm, Undated; Studio Ugur Gunyuz, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gatherings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A male with a fez and a mustache in traditional dress. 23.5 x 18.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Fezes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Mustaches; Ottoman Clothing; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Traditional Dress; Turkey
- Seated couple, man in suit and round sunglasses seated in front of a table with newspaper and fruit. 32.7 x 26.3 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Couple; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Newspapers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- A group of men in suits. 27.4 x 33.5 cm, Undated; Studio Foto Rekor, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Ankara, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits; Turkish Writing
- A group of men with Turkish flags on a table and a Turkish flag hanging on the wall in the background. Turkish writing on the back, 15/10/1961 on the day of general elections and signatures. 26.2 x 32.2 cm, 15 October 1961; Studio Foto Hilal, Bakirkoy, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Elections; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Political Life; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing
- Man with slicked back hair, a bow tie and a pocket square. 28.9 x 19.9 cm, 1914; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Bow Ties; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Bride in a white ruffled hat and a string of pearls, surrounded by family members. 19.5 x 25.5 cm, 26 September 1948; Studio Saraef, Sisli, Stanbul, Turkey (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Armenian Writing; Brides; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils
- Young seated female with black knee high boots and a black skirt. Turkish writing on the back. 13.3 x 8.3 cm, 10 October 1972; Studio Foto Muzaffer, Turkey (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Bolu, Turkey; Boots; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- A young boy with a bow tie and belt on a pedestal. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Bow Ties; Children; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- A female in a dark dress with dark lipstick, male in a dark suit with a short mustache. 8.5 x 11.6 cm, Undated; Studio Foto Sabah, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Couple; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- Two young girls one in light dress with bow on her head, older female in dark dress with buttons.13.4 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Studio Kenan, Turkey (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Children; Family; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Two young boys in sailor suits. 13.8 x 8.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Boys; Children; Family; Gelatin Silver Prints; Maritime Outfits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Young girls in uniforms in a classroom, girls in back are giving bunny ears. 9.0 x 14.0 cm, October 1971; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Uniforms
- Young girls in white P.E. uniforms walking in rows at a stadium. Writing on reverse, "19 May Commemoration of Atatürk, Youth and Sports Day Celebrations". 9.0 x 14.0 cm, Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Mustafa Kemal Ataturk, 1881-1938; Photographic Prints; Sports; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- Young boy and older male is seated in a suit with tie and pocket square. 13.5 x 8.7 cm, 19 December 1952; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Boys; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iskenderun, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkish Writing
- Older male in Western suit is holding a young boy in a white outfit. 13.5 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Boys; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Newspapers; Photographic Prints; Suits; Turkey
- Family group, two young children sitting on a bench in front of a couple. 14.3 x 7.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Children; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- A bride and groom are standing. 13.5 x 8.3 cm, 10 December 1949; Studio Photo Moda, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Couple; Flowers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Wedding Portraits
- A young female with a hat and her hands in her coat pockets. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Moda, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Coats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Hats; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- A young couple, woman has arms crossed. 13.5 x 8.7 cm, 18 October 1929; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Couple; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- A female in a dark flowery dress with a dark purse and white gloves held in her right hand. 13.7 x 8.5 cm, 30 June 1941; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Fashion Accessories; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gloves; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Women
- A female in a white apron and dark dress in front of a window with lace curtains. 11.9 x 9.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Women
- A young couple, female is wearing a dark coat, with a hat and blusher. 8.8 x 13.4 cm, Undated; Studio Kenan, Turkey (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Coats; Couple; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- A male, holding baby in white outfit, two younger females in belted dresses. 14.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Children; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- Two females in a park, older woman is in a dark coat with a white head scarf. 14.1 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Family; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Head Covers; Parks; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Women
- A group of twelve males in suits. One is wearing a military uniform. 8.5 x 13.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Military; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Soldiers; Suits; Turkey; Uniforms
- A woman with crossed arms standing in a corner. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Women
- A family walking in winter coats outside. 8.7 x 13.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Coats; Family; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Parks; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- A group of men, women and children inside a home. Older man in the middle with a light suit, young female in the front with a light flowered dress on. 8.5 x 13.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Ceremony; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Women
- A young female sitting on a garden wall in front of some wooden houses. 13.8 x 8.9 cm, 28 December 1954; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Architecture; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Women
- A male wearing round, dark glasses and a robe with a sash over his shoulder. 13.5 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Studio Foto Sabah, Istanbul, Turkey (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Law; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- A female seated on a sofa wearing a dark dress with a light colar. Sofa has geometric patterns on the seat. 12.8 x 8.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Women
- A male wearing a Western suit, standing in front of a river with houses in the background. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Architecture; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Lakes; Men; Photographic Prints
- Four women in a row boat. 9.0 x14.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Bathing Suits; Boats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Women
- A group of children in front of house with a sewing machine on a table. 8.9 x 13.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Architecture; Children; Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Sewing; Turkey
- A couple seated with a child on a blanket in a garden. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, 18 July 1931; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Family; Family Portraits; French Writing; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- A group of males gathered around a table with bunk beds in the rooms. 8.9 x 13.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)